LEO THOMAS

DATA SCIENTIST - SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Washington D.C.

leo thomas101@yahoo.com



415.384.1895



https://github.com/leothomas

Python

SUMMARY:

Data scientist and software engineer searching for a data engineering or related position. Extensive knowledge of AWS, python data ecosystem and webscraping in context of startups (AI, drone technology, distributed manufacturing), opensourced software (neuro-informatics) and research (quantum computation). McGill Physics and CS grad (2017).

EXPERIENCE:

DATA SCIENTIST / BACKEND ENGINEER

NAR Technologies (startup)

Sep. 2018 - Sep. 2019 Beirut, Lebanon

- Refactored AWS backend for mobile application, reducing operation costs by ~85%, by migrating to a DynamoDB (NoSQL) database and AppSync (GraphQL) API
- Implemented autoscaling AWS resource provisioning and versioned updates of AWS backend by using Troposphere (Python) to generate Cloudformation templates
- · Implemented generation of KML reports to visualize drone imaging data
- Created a Docker image with a local instance of the AWS database and API using Flask (Python), for development and testing
- Designed architecture for product licensing and implemented Stripe payment system
- Spearheaded implementation of agile methodologies (UI / UX, scrum / sprint)

DATA SCIENTIST / SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

3D4Pro (startup)

Oct. 2017 - Jun. 2018 Paris, France

- · Analyzed and proposed improvements to 3D modeling time estimates using statistical analysis and machine learning (Sklearn, Jupyter)
- Designed and implemented webscrapers to automate market data collection (Selenium. Tor, Pandas). Organized data into dashboards for CRM and BI (Elasticsearch, Kibana)
- · Contributed to client facing webapp (node.js/vue.js) frontend and AWS backend
- Implemented a CI pipeline for update deployments (Gitlab pipeline)

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER INTERN

McGill Centre for Integrative Neuroscience

May 2017 - Aug. 2017 Montreal. Canada

- · Developed a module for quality control of medical imaging and patient data (Php, MySQL)
- Developed a data visualization tool for the Infant Brain Imaging Study (Python, Matplotlib)

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER INTERN

Identify3D (startup)

May 2015 - Aug. 2015 San Francisco, California

- Created a new user interface for encryption software (Java / JSwing)
- · Automated and documented the setup of AWS webservers for product demos
- · Maintained and operated 3D printers, managed customer orders

BARISTA – Starbucks

May 2014 - Aug. 2014

EDUCATION:

MCGILL UNIVERSITY

BSc. Physics and Computer Science (joint major)

Sep. 2013 - May 2017 Montreal, Canada

- · Coursework in Physics (theoretical / experimental), Math (including Statistics) and CS
- 6 month exchange at **Universidad Del Salvador** (Buenos Aires, Argentina)

RESEARCH:

MCGILL UNIVERSITY

Quantum NanoElectronics Laboratory

on keyword searches (Selenium, Tkinter)

Sep. 2016 - Dec. 2016 Montreal, Canada

 Developed a numerical simulation to study the effect of static disorder on quantum particle entanglement (Python, SciPy, Matplotlib)

Developed a webscraper to gather content and metadata of public LinkedIn posts based

FREELANCE:

LINKEDIN WEBSCRAPER

May 2017

AWS	•	•	•	•	0
Git	•	•	•	•	0
Unix / Linux	•	•	•	•	0
Elasticsearch / Kibana	•	•	•	0	0
Docker	•	•	0	0	0
JavaScript	•	•	0	0	0
Java / MySQL / Php	•	0	0	0	0

LANGUAGES:

French	•	•	•	•	•
English	•	•	•	•	•
Spanish	•	•	•	•	0
Arabic (Lebanese)	•	0	0	0	0

* Dual citizen (USA / France)

GITHUB PROJECTS:

Simple Neural Network (Python):

Neural network created from scratch to better understand gradient descent and back-propagation. Now developing a genetic algorithm to teach it to play Snake.

Fire Simulation (Python):

Coach (ages 8-12)

Numerical simulation of a forest fire spreading through a procedurally generated terrain (Perlin Noise) using a BFS algorithm. Created to better understand numerical simulations and graph traversal.

WATER POLO:

INTERESTS:

Player	May 2017
Libellule De Paris	Paris, France
Player	2013 – 2017
McGill Poseidon	Montreal, Canada
Coach (ages 8-12)	2011 – 2013

Mill Valley, CA Soma Aquatics

Cooking • Travel • Guitar • Literature